# Michael Stokley

Seattle, WA

(303) 801-8575 • mastokley

## **Profile**

Software developer. I'm patient enough to take difficult projects seriously, and driven enough to automate tedious, needlessly manual work. In my previous accounting position, I greatly exceeded expectations by teaching myself SQL and relational database theory in order to automate the vast majority of my data entry and data quality tasks, and avoid using a cumbersome GUI. Since then, I spent two years studying math, computer science, and statistics at North Seattle College, attended Code Fellows' Python Development Intensive (taught by esteemed pythonista Cris Ewing), and have independently studied the classic textbook The Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs. Recently, I helped to co-found a local big data/nlp startup, and have been working as a freelance web developer.

## Technical Skills

**Proficient Familiar** 

JavaScript, Vue.js, Git, SQL, HTML/CSS, Unix systems, Bash

Python, Django, Django REST Framework, Flask, PostgreSQL, Webpack, Mocha/Chai, AWS Deployment, Heroku Deployment, Ansible, Nginx, Gunicorn, MongoDB, Pyramid, Scheme

## **Experience**

Full Stack Engineer

iDatalabs, Bellevue, WA 2017.01 - present

I built and maintain a Vue.js app to display and sell marketing data; I also maintain and update the consumed api (written in Flask).

Designed and implemented a store to manage client-side shared state

#### Freelance Web Developer

Red Mountain Software, Seattle, WA

2016.08 - 2016.10

Designed, built, and tested an internal management application according to client specification. App built with Django and PostgreSQL, with jQuery on the front as needed.

- Designed and implemented database schema
- Wrote models, views, and templates
- Wrote a method to display arbitrary model fields (including reverse relationships) for arbitrary models

#### **Co-founding Software Developer**

Sternshus, Inc, Seattle, WA

2016.07 - 2016.09

Provided front-end solutions in the context of rapidly changing business requirements. Worked primarily in Webflow, Django, and MySQL. I am most proud of having written sed and python scripts to automate merging Webflow files into the larger Django project.

## **Projects**

### Reciprocity

github.com/TeamReciprocity/reciprocity

2016.04

A full stack Python web application for recipe sharing and collaboration. Built with Django and PostgreSQL, deployed via Ansible to an AWS EC2 instance.

## Toy Domain Scraper

github.com/mastokley/toy domain scraper

2016.04

Toy web scraper built in Python. Uses breadth-first traversal for fast, reliable results.

### **HomeQuest**

github.com/homequest/homequest

A full-stack Python web application to gamify household chores and chore management. Manually implemented authorization, authentication, and row-level security. Built in Pyramid with a PostgreSQL database and deployed on Heroku.

## Education

Code Fellows Seattle, WA

Certificate 2016

Advanced Python development emphasizing test driven development, pair programming, agile methodologies, version control, and basic data structures and algorithms

North Seattle College

Seattle, WA

Coursework in Math, Computer Science, and Statistics

2012-2014

St. John's College Annapolis, MD B. A. in Philosophy 2009